他肯定得到些内部消息
...he's definitely got the inside track.
传闻说他们深受伤病困扰
Word is they're having some problems with injuries.
真的吗?  他们不是要在最后时刻
Really? are they looking into free agent signing at
签几名自由球员吗?
The last second or anything like that?
可能吧  他们有一支训练有素的球队
Possibly, they got a strong farm club too.
随时让顶级球员替补上场
They got some aaa ball players they might be bringing up...
彼得在半小时之后
But again, peter will certianly be able tell us a little bit
会带来详细的报道
More about that in the next half hour.
你看好哪支队伍?
Who do you like?
到现在为止  我看好纽约队的表现
Well tell you, so far, I like what I'm seeing in new york.
他们跟以前一样实力雄厚
They got a strong ball club as usual.
这是美国最好的球队...
That is in the american, and..
在国家联盟里  我还是看好芝加哥
And the national, I'm still liking chicago,
遇上洛杉矶会有点小麻烦
With a little bit of twist here for los angeles.
好的  究竟纽约和芝加哥会师决赛
okay, so we're looking here at new york, chicago
还是洛杉矶充当黑马
World series, possible los angeles.
这个赛季结束就能见分晓
Hey, hold it to him to the end of the season.
现在让我们把镜头从体育播报
That's gonna do it from the sports desk for right now.
切换回直播室  谢谢戴夫
Back to you guys in the studio, thanks dave.
谢谢  艾迪  谢谢大家
Thanks for nothing eddy, thank you guys.
我们关注的不止是这些
That's not all we're following.
现在由凯伦带来健康播报
Here's karen at the health desk.
医药界已经见证了不少奇迹
The world of medicine has seen its share of miracle
从小儿麻痹疫苗到心脏移植术
Cures from the polio vaccine to heart transplants.
但过去所有的成就相比于
But all past achievements may pale
爱丽丝·克里本医生的成果就显得黯然失色
In comparison to the work of dr. alice krippin.
谢谢你今天上午接受我们的访问
thank you so much for joining us this morning.
不客气
not at all.
克里本医生  请您简单介绍一下
Dr. krippin, give it to me in a nutshell.
前提非常简单
The premise is quite simple.
利用大自然创造的东西...
Take something designed by nature ...
重新组合使其为人体
And reprogram it to make it work for
服务而不是与其作对
The body rather than against it.
你指的是病毒吗?
You're talking about a virus?
是的  这里是指麻疹病毒
indeed yes, in this case, the measles.
从基因层面改造这种病毒
A virus which has been engineered at a genetic
会变得有用而非有害
Level to be helpful rather than harmful.
我想到个很好的比喻
I find the best way to describe it is
你把自己的身体想成是一条公路
If you can imagine your body is a highway....
病毒就像是一辆快速行驶的汽车
And you picked the virus as a very fast car,
被一个坏家伙驾驶着
Being driven by a very bad man.
试想这辆车会带来多大的伤害
Imagine the damage that car can cause.
但如果你让一个警察来驾驶
But if you replace that man with a cop,
情况就有所不同了
Then the picture changes.
我们实质上就是做这些事
And that is essentially what we have done.
目前你们治疗了多少人?
and how many people have you treated so far?
到现在我们做了10009个临床试验
We have 10,009 clinical trials in humans so far.
多少人的癌症被治愈?
and how many are cancer free?
10,009.
那么你们已经攻克了癌症?
so you have actually cured cancer?
是的  是的  我们做到了
Yes yes, yes we have.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视字幕组原创翻译制作 www.YYeTs.net
三年之后
你看到了什么
What do you see?
该死
Damn.
我们走  萨曼
Let's go sam.
去吃吧  你最喜欢的做法
Here you go, just the way you like it....
好恶心
Disgusting.
让一下
Excuse me.
放松
Relax.
吃吧
There you go.
别那样  蔬菜也得吃
No, eat your vegetables.
别拨来拨去的  吃掉它们
Don't just push 'em around, eat them.
我可没说笑
I'm not playing.
吃你的蔬菜
Eat your vegetables.
否则就整晚坐在这里
Or we'll sit down here all night.
你发什么牢骚?
What are you whining about?
为什么不好好吃你的蔬菜?
Why didn't you just eat your vegetables?
好吧  听着  听着
Okay, look, look.
明晚你必须要吃
We're gonna eat twice as many vegetables
双倍的蔬菜
Tomorrow night.
成交?
Deal?
感觉不错吧
That feels good.
萨曼
Ah sam.
罗伯特  出什么事儿了?  我一直
Robert, what is happening? I've been trying
试着打你手机  总是转入语音信箱
To reach you on the cell, I keep getting the recording.
-网络断了  -爸爸  我们要去哪儿?
- the network is down.             - dad, where are we going?
我还是不习惯这身新装备
I cannot get used to the new rags.
我们要去莎拉阿姨家
we're going to aunt sarah's sweetie.
不  为什么?
No, why?!
自己系好安全带  走
just strap yourself in, go.
我们只有30分钟  上校
we're at 30 minutes colonel.
知道了
copy.
30分钟去做什么?
30 minutes to what?
他们要封锁这个岛
they're sealing off the island.
封锁这个岛?  这个岛?
seal off the island?  this island?
但我不想去莎拉阿姨家
but I don't wanna go to aunt sarah's.
你把钱都带上了吗?  有多少?
did you bring all the money?  how much?
600美元  你说"你们要走"什么意思?
600 dollars, why did you say you're going?
钱还不够
that is not enough.
罗伯特  你说"你们要走"  而不是"我们要走"
robert, you said "you're going", not "we're going".
过去后  我要你找个取款机
when you get across, I need you to get to the atm.
能取多少就取多少
Get as much cash as you can.
现在又不是夏天
it's not even summer yet.
开上莎拉的车  远离城市
take sarah's car, go upstate.
我会到农场接你们  带上足够两周的食物
I'll meet you at the farm, bring enough food for 2 weeks.
天啊  罗伯特  病毒开始蔓延了?
Jesus, robert. did it jump?
空气传播?
Is it airborne?
可我们只在夏天才去莎拉阿姨家的
but we only go to aunt sarah's in the summer.
有可能
maybe.
今天是圣诞节  我的礼物呢?
It's christmas. what about my presents?
总统宣布着这件事
he's announcing it.
不要搞错了  我的美国人民
make no mistake my fellow americans.
-我的礼物还在壁橱里  -突变的病毒是致命的
- my gifts are still in the closet.        - the mutated virus is lethal.
安静点  玛丽
hush now mar.
此事不仅关系到美国人民的生存
the survival of not only our nation, but
还关系到全世界人民
Of every other nation on the planet.
妈妈  看啊  是一只蝴蝶
mom, look. a butterfly.
玛丽  够了
marley, enough!
我怀着极为沉痛的心情和强烈的决心
So, I announce with great sadness, but even greater resolve.
今晚我签署一条行政命令
That tonight I have signed an executive order,
对纽约启动军事隔离
Initiating a military quarantine of new york city.
原上帝与我们同在
god be with us.
还有机会  我们会有办法的  也许1  2礼拜内
the window is still open, we find something in a week..or 2 weeks,
能够阻止病毒蔓延
...we can reverse the spread.
我能解决这一切
I can still fix this.
求你了  你能在市区外还是能做这些的
Please, you can do the same work outside the city.
爆心投影点  这是我的区域  我们说过的
Ground zero, this is my site. we talked about this.
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
我要做什么?
What am I doing?
我要阻止这一切的发生
I'm not gonna let this happen.
什么?  这不是你能决定的  你不能
let? this isn't up to you, you can't...
睡好了吗?
How did you sleep?
别进去  你知道的
Now come on, you know better than that.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
罗伯特·奈维尔博士  2012年9月5日  GA系列391号血清
Dr. robert neville, september 5, 2012. ga series serum 391.
动物实验  开始传输影像
Animal trials, streaming video.
结果一切如常
The results appear typical.
化合物1 3 4 6 8 9 10 11...
Compounds 1, 3, 4, 6, 8, 9, 10, 11 ...
14 16和18未能杀死病毒
14, 16 and 18 did not kill the virus.
化合物2 5 7 12 13 15 17...
Compounds 2, 5, 7, 12, 13, 15 and 17 ...
都杀死了宿主
All killed the host.
等一下
Hold on a second.
化合物6显示
Compound 6 seems to be showing decreased
攻击性减弱
Aggression response.
局部性色素回复
Partial pigmentation returned.
轻微的瞳孔收缩
Slight pupil constriction.
GA系列391号血清化合物6
Ga series serum 391 compound 6
下次用来做人体实验
Is the next candidate for human trials.
撑住啊  6号小鼠
Hang in there number 6.
想开车窗就开吧
Yeah, that's what you want.
早安  玛姬  早安  弗雷德
Good morning, marge and fred.
你们这么早来干什么啊?
What are you doing here so early?
弗雷德  运动衫不错啊
Nice sweatshirt there fred.
别把它乱放
Don't fit it down anywhere.
我们里面见
I see you inside.
怎么了  伙计?
What's happening brother?
早上好  汉克
Good morning hank.
通过G测试了
Getting through the g's.
那个女孩是谁
Who's the girl ...
算了  明早见吧
Nevermind, hey I'll see you in the morning.
-我该怎么打招呼呢?
- what am I supposed to say?
-你好  想看看被感染的老鼠吗
- hello, wanna see some infected rats.
好吧  就明天
Okay, tomorrow.
明天我就去和她打招呼
I'm going to say hello tomorrow.
干得好
You did so good.
就这样
Yes, yes.
看看  看见没有?  红鲑鱼罐头
Look at that, see that?  red salmon.
噢  肉罐头
Wow, actual spam.
你等下再吃
No, you'll get some of that later.
我们走
Let's go.
我是罗伯特·奈维尔  我是纽约的一名幸存者
I am robert neville. I am a survivor
我在AM所有频道上进行广播
I am broadcasting on all am frequencies.
每天中午我都会在南大街码头
I will be at the south street seaport everyday
如果你能听到我  如果任何人能听到我
If you are out there...if anyone is out there,
我能提供食物  我能提供住所
I can provide food, I can provide shelter,
我能提供安全保障
I can provide security.
如果有任何人能听到我  任何人
If there is anybody out there, anybody...
请回答我  你不是孤独一人
Please, you are not alone.
好好看我这球
Keep your eye on this one for me.
我打得越来越好了
I'm getting good.
来吧萨曼  必须得走了  必须得走了
Come on sam. I gotta go. I gotta go.
萨曼  出来  我们得走了
Sam, come on. we have to go.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
萨曼  我们快走!
Sam, we gotta go!
萨曼  快走  快出去!
Sam, go now, get out!
你一定要小心  知道吗?
You need to pay attention, okay?
-要小心点
- gotta pay attention.
听着  这次我要你乖乖地待在这
Listen, I want you to stay here on this one, okay?
因为你仍会被感染  而我不会
Because you can still get infected and I can't.
听着  如果天黑了我还没回来
Listen, if I am not back by dark...
你就自己走吧
Just go.
试验对象为女性
Okay, the subject is female.
大约18-20岁
Most likely 18-20 years of age.
所需注射镇静剂剂量为正常人的6倍
a lot of push effective 6 times the human dose.
体温华氏106度  脉搏每分钟200
Core temperature 106 fahrenheit, pulse 200 bpm,
呼吸急促  动脉血氧含量为正常人3倍
..respiration elevated, pao2 300% of normal.
瞳孔已完全扩张
The pupils are fully dilated.
对光线有反应
Now reactive to light.
皮肤对紫外线有强烈反应
Extreme reaction to uv exposure...
症状和组织采样表明
Symptoms and tissue samples confirm subject
她已感染KV病毒
Is infected with kv.
391号血清疫苗试验  第6号化合物
Vaccine test series serum 391 compound six.
开始人体试验
Commencing human trials.
呼吸开始变慢  脉搏190
Respiration is slowing, pulse 190,
体温105  104  继续降低
Core temperature 105, 104 and decreasing.
好像有些效果了
We may have something here.
GA系列391号血清疫苗第六号化合物  对人体无效
Ga series serum 391 compound 6,ineffective on humans.
试验结果存入链接在此机的
Test results linked to this entry,
6个备份硬盘里
Saved on 6 redundant drives.
依然无效
Still no cure.
第1001天  今天我们近距离接触一个巢穴
Day 1001: we came in close contact with a hive today.
血液试验表明  我仍然对
The blood tests confirm that I remain immune....
空气性和接触性传播免疫
For both the airborne and contact strains.
犬类仅对空气性传播免疫
Canines remain immune to airborne strain only.
傻瓜  你不能跑到阴暗的地方去
You can't go running into the dark dummy.
疫苗试验继续  可我依然无法
Vaccine trials continue.  I am still unable
将我自己的免疫能力
To transfer my immunity...
转移到被感染者的身上去  KV病毒  真的很奇妙
...to infected host.  krippin virus is....elegant.
就像在大海捞针
It's like fishing in the dark, son.
今天一个被感染女性
Um, an infected male
将自己暴露在日光下
Exposed himself to sunlight today.
有可能大脑功能退化  或是
Now it's possible that decreased brain function..or...
因为食物缺乏
Growing scarcity of food is..
导致他们忽视自己的求生本能
...is causing them to ignore their basic survival instincts.
社交能力退化已很明显
Social de-evolution appears complete.
典型人类行为已完全消失
Typical human behavior is now entirely absent.
我们为什么停下来?
Why are we stopping?
请出来
Please go
-你们只有不到10分钟时间
- you've got less than 10 minutes.
宝贝  把狗给我
Baby, give me the dog.
-我们走  宝贝  我们走
- let's go baby, let's go.
-爸爸
- daddy.
待在那附近  别让任何人靠近
Stay in my neighborhood and let nobody stop you by.
-妈妈  他们有枪
- mommy, they have guns.
-别担心  他们像爸爸一样也是军人
- it's okay, they're in the army like daddy.
请回家去
Then, please, back home.
-过来
- coming through.
如果你没有通过检查
If you are not covered by the checkpoint,
那么  请回吧
Then, please, go home.
你没问题  往前走
You're clear. go ahead.
-通过
- clear.
通过  好吧  下一个  继续走
Clear...okay, next, let's go.
不行
No good.
通过  -走
Clear - okay, go.
-我们没被感染
- we are not infected.
-请带走我的女儿
- please, please take my baby.
退后退
You have to move back.
没通过
No good.
-什么?  不!  罗伯特  罗伯特!
- what, no!  robert, robert!
手拿开  别碰我太太
Whoa, whoa, get your hands off my wife.
我是罗伯特·奈维尔上校
I'm lieutenant robert neville
把手拿开
Get your hands off me.
-再扫描她一遍
- scan her again.
-退后!
- stand down!
-退后士兵!  退后!
- stand down soldier! stand down!
-我是陆军上校罗伯特·奈维尔
- I am lieutenant-colonel robert neville.
我命令你再扫描她一遍
I order you to scan her again.
再扫描她一遍!
Scan her again!
-好吧  再扫描一遍
- alright, scan her again.
通过  没问题  过去吧
Clear, it's clear, move through.
爸爸  我们为什么不能回自己的家?
Dad, why can't we go to our home too?
-还有多久?
- how long?
-5分钟  来得及
- five minutes, we'll make it.
621  我们已到
621. we are on site.
我会好好照顾她们的  上校
I won't take my eyes off them colonel.
我向你保证
You got my word on it.
亲一下
Give me a kiss.
小心点  -你也是
Be careful. - you too.
-上帝啊  请保佑罗伯特
- dear god, please watch over robert,
赋予他勇气去战胜一切难题
Keep him strong for the struggle ahead of him lord.
请把他安全地带回来  阿门
Please, just bring him home safely, amen.
爸爸去把那些怪物消灭掉  好吗?
Daddy's going to make the monsters go away baby, okay?
-萨曼  你去保护爸爸
- sam, you protect daddy.
-不  亲爱的  我不能带着狗!
- no baby, I can't take the dog!
长官  我们得走了
Sir, we have to go.
爸爸  你看  一只蝴蝶
Dad, look, a butterfly.
-你睡得怎么样?  -罗伯特·奈维尔博士正在仔细观察
- how'd you sleep?     - dr. robert neville will be taking a closer look
爱丽丝·克里本博士研究的病毒变化
...at the ongoing mutations of dr. alice krippin's
那曾经一度奇迹般治愈癌症
Once hailed miracle cure for cancer.
到目前为止  大约5000名病人感染变种的病毒
So far, almost 5000 patients treated with a
他们已经显现出类似早期狂犬病症状
Retrofitted virus, had begun exhibiting symptoms
目前已有25名病人死亡
25 patients have already died.
奈维尔博士已命令当地医院储存好抗病毒药物
Dr. neville has ordered local hospitals to stockpile
并准备实施初步的检疫隔离方案
Antiviral drugs, and to begin preliminary quarantine protocol....
-今天是我生日
- it's my birthday today.
-我们完全相信奈维尔博士能带领我们...
- we are fully confident dr. neville can see us through...
-想唱歌吗?
- would you like to sing?
我是罗伯特·奈维尔  我是纽约的一名幸存者
My name is robert neville, I am a survivor living in new york city.
我在AM所有频道上进行广播
I am broadcasting on all am frequencies.
每天中午我都会在南大街码头
I will be at the south street seaport everyday, midday,
中午艳阳高照的时候
When the sun is highest in the sky.
如果你能听到我  如果任何人能听到我
If you are out there....if anyone is out there....
我能提供食物  我能提供住所
I can provide food, I can provide shelter,
我能提供安全保障
I can provide security.
如果有任何人能听到我  任何人
If there's anybody out there, anybody...
请回答我  你不是孤独一人
Please, you are not alone.
听着  如果你想要开个聚会或是其他什么
Listen, if you're planning a party or something,
现在就告诉我
Just tell me now.
因为我并不喜欢惊喜  但我发誓
Okay, because I don't like surprises, and I swear
我能表现得很惊讶  好吗?
I'll act surprised. okay?
弗雷德  你在这里干什么?
What are you doing out here fred?
你在这搞什么鬼  不!
What the hell are you.....no!
-不  不!
- no! no!
弗雷德  你究竟在这儿干嘛?
What the hell are you doing out here fred!?!
你怎么到这儿来的?
How did you get out here?!?
弗雷德  如果你还活着  最好马上告诉我!
Fred, if you're real, you better tell me right now!
如果你还活着  最好马上告诉我!
If you're real, you better tell me right now!
他妈的  弗雷德
Damn, fred.
我没事
I'm okay.
过来  萨曼
Come on, sam.
过来
Come on.
萨曼  我们走!
Let's go sam!
萨曼  快走  我们得回家了
No, no, let's go sam, we gotta go home sam.
我们走
Let's go.
你没事的
Okay, you're alright.
你没事的  你没事的
It's okay. you're alright.
你一定会没事儿的
You're alright.
萨曼塔  萨曼塔
Samantha, samantha.
看着我  宝贝  你不会有事的
Look at me girl. hey, you're okay.
萨曼塔  我带你回家
Samantha, just gotta get you home.
带你回家  带你回家
Gotta take you home, take you home.
好了  来吧
Alright, come here.
到这儿来  好样的
Come here, come here, got you.
没事儿的
It's okay.
我向朋友保证  会和你
I promised my friend.... that I would say hello...
今天打招呼的
To you today.
请和我问好啊
Please say hello to me.
去死!
Die!
听见我说话吗?
Can you hear me?
坚持一下
Stick with me.
你住哪儿?
Where you live?
11号
Eleven...Eleven
华盛顿广场11号
Washington and square.
他们不知道我住哪儿
They don't know where I live.
别让他们追踪到
Don't let them track us.
等到清晨再回去
You must stay in till dawn.
恐怕鸡蛋煎的太烂了
I'm afraid the eggs are powdered, obviously
不过你知道的  这份是你的
You know that.  they're yours.
但我竟然找到了培根
But I did find bacon.  I just found the most
这可能是史上最好的事儿了
Fantastic thing in history.
我还在浴室里找到些抗生素
I found some antibiotics in the bathroom, I put
食物盛在你盘子里了  你的腿好的差不多了
By your plate because your leg is okay,
但如果不及时开始治疗
But you won't be for very long, if you don't
情况会变得糟糕的
Start a course very soon.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是安娜  这是伊桑
I am anna and this is ethan.
不吃这些要凉了
They're going to get cold.
没事儿  你坐啊
It's okay.  go on.
我们来自马里兰州
We come from maryland.
我们听到了你的广播
We heard your message heard on the radio.
我们中午就到了码头  在那儿等了你一天
We were at the pier at noon, we waited all day.
我们打算去佛蒙特州
We're going to vermont.
那个幸存者隔离区
To the survivor's colony.
在贝索尔市  那是个安全的地方
In bethel. it is a safe zone.
根本没有幸存者隔离区  更别说安全的地方了
There's no survivor's colony, no safe zone.
整件事没按原计划发展
Nothing's happening the way it was supposed to happen.
也没按原计划执行
Nothing worked the way it was supposed to work.
在山上  有一群没有被感染的人
in the mountains, there is a whole colony of
建成的隔离区
People there who didn't get sick.
病毒不能在寒冷的环境里滋长蔓延
The virus couldn't survive the cold, there's a whole...
闭嘴!
shut up!
所有人都死了
Everybody's dead.
让我静一下好吗?
I just need a minute, okay?
我只是
Just....
我一直留着那块培根
I just, I was saving that bacon.
一直留着舍不得吃
I was saving it.
我要上楼去了
I'm gonna go upstairs, alright, just.
我得上去了
I'm gonna go.
伊桑  把刀放下
Ethan, put that knife down.
能和你说话吗?
can I say something to you?
你刚才真的太不可思议了
You was really really something back there.
你在和...我说话?
Are you talking to...me?
是的  你对付那些侍卫时真厉害
Can I tell you that you were great? those guards.
他们自以为很强
They thought that they were tough.
但是你一出现他们就全跑了
And when you came and they were nowhere.
真有意思
That was fun to see.
感觉棒极了  自由的感觉真好
That's great. seriously.    -- it is nice to be free.
去和你的朋友庆祝自由吧
Why don't you celebrate your freedom
和朋友一同去?
With your own friends?  hmm?
我没有朋友  我也不想
But I have no friends. and I am not going
单独一个人走
Out there by myself.
等下  我有个好主意
Wait, I have a great idea.
我可以和你一起走
I'll stick with you.
我喜欢史瑞克
I like shrek.
你不太记得如何与人相处了  对吗?
You are not as good with people anymore are you?
谢谢你为我处理伤口
Thank you for my leg.
你都经历了些什么?
Where have you been?
我之前在圣保罗的红十字会救援船
I was on a red cross evacuation ship out of saint paolo.
那些船不会支撑太久的
those boats weren't meant to be permanent.
是的  没错
no they weren't.
当那些海军被干掉后  我们去船上抢供给
When the navy fell apart, we set on dock to get supplies.
一些人在岸上被感染了
Someone picked it up on shore.
我们有五人免疫
5 of us were immune.
-你说有五人  -他们被追随者捉住了
You said five. -- the dark seekers got them.
你是罗伯特·奈维尔  对吗?
You are the robert neville, aren't you?
今天太晚了  如果我们明天清晨出发
It's too late today. if we leave tomorrow at dawn,
就可以一路驱车到达佛蒙特州
We can make it to vermont in a straight shot.
如果...
So if we ...
我不会离开的
I'm not leaving.
这是"爆心投影点"  我的地盘
This is ground zero. this is my site.
我不会让病毒肆虐的
I'm not gonna let this happen.
我还能补救
I can still fix this.
你吓到我了
Oh, you scared me.
抱歉
sorry.
我喊了两次都没反映
I called down twice.
谢谢你
oh thank you.
她打了重度镇静剂  别担心  很安全的
That's heavily sedated, don't worry it's safe.
我从未见过他们如此平静
I've never seen one so still.
他们总是攻击咬人
They're always biting.
你认为这样能治愈她吗
Do you think that can cure her?
不  这绝对能杀了病毒
No, this will almost certainly kill it
但如果降低了她的体温
but it's possible by drastically reducing
可能可以提高疫苗的功效
Her body temperature, I can increase the compound's effectiveness.
他们都死了吗?
Did all of them die?
是的
yes.
我的上帝
My god.
上帝可不会做这些  安娜
god didn't do this anna.
我们一手造成的
We did.
伊桑能睡哪儿?
Where can ethan sleep?
他可真重
He is heavy.
你能
Can you ...
她真可爱  叫什么名字?
She is beautiful. what's her name?
玛丽  她叫玛丽
marley. Her name is marley
-很好听的名字
- it's a beautiful name.
我们用鲍勃·玛丽的名字为她取名
Yeah, we named her after bob marley.
谁?
Who?
-那个歌星
- the singer.
戴米恩?
Damian?
-是他的父亲
- his father.
他的父亲
His father.
真让人难以接受
That is unacceptable.
-怎么了?
- what?
史上最好听专辑
Best album ever made.
想起来没?
You recognize that?
他有一种想法  类似病毒学家的想法
He had this idea, it was kind of a virologist idea.
他认为  我们只要将音乐和爱
He believed that you could cure racism
注入人们的生活
And hate, literally cure it, by
就能治愈  种族歧视和仇恨
Injecting music and love into people's lives.
有一次他要在一个和平集会中表演
One day, he was scheduled to perform at a peace rally,
一个持枪歹徒闯进他家  将他射击在地
A gunman came to his house and shot him down.
两天后他依旧上台演出
Two days later he walked out on that stage and sang.
有人问他  为什么这样做
Somebody asked him, why.
"那些想要破坏世界的人
"the people who are trying to make
并没有休息"
This world worse....
"那我怎么能休息呢?"
...are not taking a day off. how can i?"
他照亮黑暗
Light up the darkness.
跟我们一起走吧  奈维尔
Come with us, neville.
去隔离区那儿
To the colony.
根本就没有隔离区  安娜
There is not a colony, anna.
一切都已经破碎瓦解了  也没有什么疏散计划
Everything just fell apart, there was no evacuation.
-你错了  有隔离区
- wrong, there is a colony.
我知道的
I know okay?
-你怎么知道的  安娜?
- how do you know, anna?
我就是知道
I just know.
我说了  你怎么知道的
How, I said how do you know?
-你怎么可能知道呢?
- how could you know?
上帝告诉我的  他有个计划
God told me, he has a plan.
上帝告诉你的  就那个上帝?
God told you? the god?
-是的
- yes.
我知道这听起来
I know how this sounds.
-很疯狂
- it sounds crazy.
但是有人告诉我打开收音机
But something told me to turn on the radio.
有人告诉我来到这里
Something told me to come here.
-我在收音机里的声音告诉你来这里的  安娜
- my voice on the radio told you to come here anna.
昨晚你试图自杀  对吗?
You were trying to kill yourself last night, right?
-安娜
- anna.
而我恰好赶到那儿救了你
And I got here just in time to save your life.
-你认为这只是巧合吗?
- do you think it is a coincidence?
别再说了
Just stop it.
-上帝驱使我来这儿
- he must have sent me here for a reason.
奈维尔  现在世界平和多了
Neville, the world is quieter now.
你只要用心去倾听
You just have to listen.
如果我们用心听了  就能听到上帝的计划
If we listen, we can hear god's plan.
上帝的计划  好  我来告诉你上帝的计划
God's plan? alright, let me tell you about your god's plan.
当感染来的时候  世界一共有60亿人口
We were 6 billion people on earth when the infection hit.
KV病毒有90%的致死率  意味着54亿人口将会死去
Kv had a 90% kill rate, that is 5.4 billion people.
乱冲乱撞  流血致死
Dead.  crashed and bled out...dead.
只有少于1%的人免疫  留下1200万的人活下来
Less than 1% immunity.  that is 12 million healthy people
就像你  我  还有伊桑
Like you, me, and ethan.
其他5.8亿人  变成了你所说的追随者
The other 588 million turned into your dark seekers.
他们饥饿恐慌  然后
And then they got hungry, and
想要吃掉每一个活着的人
They killed, and fed on everybody.
每一个人  每一个你和我
Everybody. every single person that you or i
认识的人  都死了!
Has ever known...is dead!!
死了!
Dead!
根本没有上帝
There is no god.
什么声音?
What is that?
你昨晚带我回来的时候
Was it still dark when you brought
天还是黑的吗?
Us home last night?
你当时在流血  地平线上已经露出曙光
You were bleeding, there was light on the horizon.
把灯关掉
Turn the light off.
关掉
Turn it off.
他们跟着我们回来了
They followed us home.
你还好吧?
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
嗯
yes.
去实验室  在楼下
Go to the lab. downstairs.
快走!  去实验室  去实验室
Go! to the lab. to the lab.
别让他们跟进来
Get behind them plates.
来吧  快点
come on.
快点  好了
Come on. it is okay.
起作用了
It's working.
它起作用了
停!
Stop.
我可以救你们  我可以救你们
I can save you. I can help you.
你们被感染了  我可以救你们
You are sick and I can help you.
我能做到的!
I can fix this!
我能救每一个人!
I can save everybody!
我能做到的
I can fix this.
它生效了
It's working.
停
Stop.
我能救你们  让我救你们
I can save you. let me save you.
爸爸  看啊  一只蝴蝶
Dad, look, a butterfly.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我的血里有抗体
the cure is in my blood.
进去  你们会很安全的
Go, you're going to be safe.
伊桑进去
Ethan get in.
进去
Go inside.
安娜  我认为这是你到这儿来的原因
Anna, I think this is why you're here.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我在倾听
I'm listening.
奈维尔  这里还有地方  进来吧
Neville, there is room in here, come on.
-他们不会罢休的
- they're not gonna stop.
呆到黎明再出来
Stay until dawn.
2009年  一种致命的病毒肆虐全世界
In 2009, a deadly virus burned through our civilization.
几乎将我们人类推进灭绝的边缘
Pushing humankind to the edge of extinction.
罗伯特·奈维尔医生奉献了他的生命
Dr. robert neville dedicated his life
为了找出拯救人类的解药
To the discovery of a cure.
和延续全人类的文明
And the restoration of humanity.
2012年9月12日
On september 9, 2012 ...
晚上8点49分左右
At approximately 8:49 p.m.,
他找到了解药
He discovered that cure.
8点52分  他为了保护这解药而牺牲
And at 8:52, he gave his life to defend it.
他拯救了我们
We are his legacy.
-这就是他的传奇
- this is his legend.
他点亮了黑暗
Light up the darkness.